# Khalid Abdikarim



qeys80@gmail.com



+252615803731



linkedin.com/in/khalid-abdikarim-5a9a42213



https://khalid-portofolio.netlify.app/

# Summary

A Software Engineer with experience working in programming, software development, and consulting. Holds comprehensive technical capability skills and strong knowledge of programming, software, and website development. Dedicated to meeting customer requirements with innovative solutions that maximize efficiency and exceed capability targets.

# **Experience**



## υρ Software Engineer

Upwork

Mar 2021 - Present (2 years 2 months)

Design and develop applications for clients on a short- or long-term contract basis.

Developing new or modifying existing software according to client's needs and expectations.

Troubleshooting and updating the existing applications.

Analyzing computer specifications and layouts to build a better system.

Perform code walk-throughs to ensure code correctness.

Work with other engineers to architect, build, and test new features.

Work in an agile environment to release software on a regular schedule.



# IT Support Specialist

#### Faruq Public Notary

Nov 2017 - Jan 2019 (1 year 3 months)

Installs new hardware and software and maintains existing components.

Trains end users in the use of equipment and software.

Investigated incidents caused by malicious activities and identify false positives.

Performs general maintenance tasks troubleshoots and resolves issues with user devices and peripheral equipment located throughout the notary.

Reviewed procedures and made recommendations to management to streamline operations.

Prepare communication, reports, presentations, and other products by operating Microsoft Word, Excel, and Powerpoint.



#### **Network Technician**

SomStar internet service provider (ISP)

Feb 2016 - Aug 2017 (1 year 7 months)

Provided well-functioning network support for business and residential clients

Performed troubleshooting and equipment diagnostics in order to resolve connectivity issues

Set up new networking systems designed to suit the client's needs and budget

Installed and configured computer hardware and software, optimized network performance, and created firewalls that prevented access to unauthorized internet content

Provided troubleshooting and repair as needed

#### **Education**

#### Universiti Putra Malaysia

Master's degree, Software Engineering

Sep 2019 - Sep 2021

During this period, I have learned different courses required to be a Master of Software Engineering. The most important thing you will learn first is how to conduct research as the university focuses on research. In Universiti Putra Malaysia (UPM), students have to come up with a research project in each subject to pass these courses. In addition, during my study, my research paper has been accepted for presentation at the International Conference on Engineering Technology (ICET 2021), and then published in International Journal of Synergy in Engineering and Technology. Therefore, this experience helped me to gain extensive experience in research.

## SIMAD University

Computer science and Information technology, General

Sep 2011 - Jan 2016

This is where my journey of studying computer science has started and they really provided me with the tools that I needed to choose the right direction and successfully complete my first bachelor degree in computer science

# Al-imam ibnukhuzeyma

High School

Aug 2007 - May 2011

I graduated from this school starting from my primary to secondary.

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

**English Certificate: ELS Selangor-Malaysia** - Universiti Putra Malaysia: (In this college, i have gained my English certificate which is equivalent to 6 IELTS score. this certificate was required in order to start my master's degree.)

# Routing switching and wireless networking - SIMAD University

#### Skills

Research • Agile Methodologies • Web Development • MERN Stack • Git & GitHub • Computer Network Operations • Computer Hardware Troubleshooting • Good communication • Teamwork and interpersonal

#### **Honors & Awards**

Best paper award - 5th international conference on engineering technology (ICET)

Oct 2021

The International Conference on Information Technology (ICIT2021) aims to exchange and share their experiences and research results in all aspects of information technology, software, computer application and other related areas through oral and poster presentation.